Application Letter

bethelhemmanaye@gmail.com

Electrical and Computer Engineer

Dear Mr. / Miss.

It looks like you have a new vacancy related to my field of study, and I am eagerly looking forward to

our collaboration.

I am now a generation; do not tell me you want 15 years of experience. All I need is an opportunity to

prove myself, we all know experience makes perfect, let me share a story.

There is a great story about the CEO of IBM in his sixties, Tom Watson Junior, that goes like this: a young

executive had made some bad decisions that cost the company several million dollars. He was summoned to

Watson's office, fully expecting to be fired. As he entered the office, the young executive said," I suppose

after that set of mistakes you will want to fire me, and I completely understand it". To which Watson replied.

"Not at all young man, we have just spent a couple of million dollars educating you, now we need you to put

this education to work".

Young people need an opportunity, time to prove themselves, trust, someone who believes, and a good boss

who follows, so give me an opportunity. I appreciate it.

Please find attached my resume and cover letter. I look forward to meeting you in person to discuss an

opportunity.

"I like to think I am an engineer not the person who takes engineering course"

Sincerely,

Bethlehem Manaye

Bethlehem Manaye

C.M.C, Addis Ababa 0912870652-911097152

⊠ <u>bethelhemmanaye@g</u>

• Bethlehemmanay

in Bethlehem Manaye

EXPERIENCE

Addisber.com, Addis Ababa Hayat — IT Officer

JUNE 2021- OCTOBER 2021

It was my first paid job and I have a good experience.

DAN Energy, Addis Ababa C.M.C — Software Engineer

DECEMBER 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

It was an interesting experience and I think I learn more about myself and what I looking for in life.

iCog-labs, Addis Ababa Dembel — ML Engineer

AUGUST 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

I was in an internship program and I have excellent experience in working under pressure and part of the team, have learned Artificial Intelligence courses, DOBOT ROBOT and Robot Operating System (ROS).

EDUCATION

Aksum University, Aksum Ethiopia — Degree

SEPTEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2021

Bachelor of Science Electrical and Computer Engineering focused

Computer area, Cumulative Grade Point (CGPA2.83).

SATcom, Addis Ababa — Certificate

DECEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Computer Maintenance and Networking.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS,
 JavaScript and React
- Python, and Machine Learning
- Nodejs, Express, and EJS
- SQL and NoSQL

WORK STYLE

- Perfectionist
- Learner
- Hard Worker
- Highly Critical

LANGUAGES

- Amharic Native fluency
- English good fluency

OTHER THINGS

- Tutorial for different grade level students
- Interested in maths, physics, and art

Aksum University, Aksum — *Certificate*

MARCH 2018 - MAY 2019

CCNA Routing and Switching course as part of the Cisco Networking Academy.

PROJECTS

Automatic Toll Collection System

 Automatic Tool Collection System with Microcontroller is a system that has sensors and Radio Frequency Identification(RFID)

Breast Cancer Prediction

 Breast Cancer Analysis and Prediction with Machine Learning Algorithm. It predicts malignant and benign tumors

Personal Portfolio

Personal portfolio with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with some UI materials

Amazon-Clone — & EJS, CSS Challenge

- Amazon-Clone with javaScript libraries React
- To do list, Daily Journal and other projects using EJS, Express, and Nodejs

Car Recognizing

 Car Recognizing and Counting System using python openCV and car cascading classifiers this ensemble learning based on the trained classifiers.